crystal2cross@gmail.com (323) 316-5220 crystal2cross.github.io

SUMMARY

With an engineer's mind, artist's eye, and empathetic heart, I am a designer who champions for great user experiences.

PORTFOLIO

Lead Designer & Developer, Street Sheet | View Case Study: http://crystal2cross.github.io/streetsheet.html

Designed and implemented a responsive website for a biweekly San Francisco newspaper that is an extension of their print newspaper, archiving all articles with additional web-only content and optimized for all screen sizes.

UX Designer, Homes.com | View Case Study: http://crystal2cross.github.io/homeshare.html

Designed a companion website for Homes.com to help people who can't afford to buy a home, find and meet people to join forces and buy their dream home with. Deliverables included personas, journey maps, wireframes, and click-through prototype.

UX Designer, Progress Hardware | View Case Study: http://crystal2cross.github.io/progress-hardware.html

Designed an ecommerce website for a brick and mortar hardware store. Deliverables included navigation system, streamlined checkout process, wireframes, and click-through prototype.

SKILLS

UX: Information Architecture, User Research, Personas, Rapid Prototyping, Wireframes, Usability Testing

Tools: Sketch3, InVision, Paper Prototyping

Technical: HTML, CSS (Sass), JavaScript (AngularJS, Backbone.Marionette), Java, Scala, PHP, Git

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

General Assembly, User Experience Design Immersive

March 2016 - May 2016

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Designer & Developer

May 2016 – Present

Software Engineer | AppDirect | www.appdirect.com

April 2015 - February 2016

AppDirect is a cloud service commerce platform provider enabling people to create, find, buy and manage software in the cloud. As a member of multiple engineering teams, I helped to: develop AppDirect's OAuth management panel; design and implement a themed partner marketplace for Hawaiian Telecom; and troubleshoot issues and bugs for existing partners. Technologies used: Javascript, HTML, CSS (Sass), Backbone.Marionette, and Java.

Web Application Developer | Sungevity | www.sungevity.com

June 2014 – April 2015

Sungevity is a solar power provider helping the world run on the sun. As a member of multiple engineering teams, I helped to develop their customer portal and Instant IQuote (IIQ) iPad web application. Developing for IIQ, I was responsible for the user flow and interface of the application, and development was iterative, with real-time feedback from field members using the app in Lowes hardware stores and at Sungevity marketing events. Technologies used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JQuery Mobile, AngularJS, Scala, Play (Scala Web Framework), and PHP.

Mobile Web Developer Internship | Moovweb | www.moovweb.com

March 2014 - June 2014

Moovweb is a platform enabling businesses to transform their desktop-only websites to mobile and tablet experiences. As a member of a 3-person developer team, we transformed Forever21's website utilizing JavaScript, HTML, CSS (Sass), and various JavaScript libraries including jQuery, Tritium, and Uranium.

EDUCATION